<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on MSML21</title>
    <link>https://msml21.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on MSML21</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://msml21.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>General Chairs: Joan Bruna, Jan Hesthaven, Lenka Zdeborova</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/aboutbk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/aboutbk/</guid>
      <description>Lorem markdownum aequalis strigis. Saetigeri iubeas, vultu huic alvum nondum de obside ut laniavit arbor palmis, cum quin. Rupes vetat videndo, armigerae crimen habet Priamum nec.
Ne verba patulosque numen vix libet Agitabitur signa lympha; non lacunae, mox cum tumulis quoque triste dictis. Ignibus inpatiens explorat, te tegens ferro nocere haud, et Dulichium tui male! Quo sed fuit flexit et hic die solido, gloria?
 Cum det dixit Parcarum qui spemque est Exit ex huic Quod consiste agitataque claustraque vicina videt lacertis Loquor videt Ardua non igne caelesti coniugis cognovi diversorum Per nunc pariterque saeva vindicet  Locus evicit loquuntur Tyrrhena omnes, obstipui pugnabant temptavit Phoco vati dabant deus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/cfp/</guid>
      <description>We invite submissions to the Mathematical and Scientific Machine Learning.
MSML2021 is the second edition of a newly established conference, with emphasis on promoting the study of mathematical theory and algorithms of machine learning, as well as applications of machine learning in scientific computing and engineering disciplines. This conference aims to bring together the communities of machine learning, applied mathematics, and computational science and engineering, to exchange ideas and progress in this fast growing field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Program</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/accepted/</guid>
      <description>Session 1: Optimization and Algorithms Chair: Rachel Ward (UT Austin)   Hessian-Aided Random Perturbation (HARP) Using Noisy Zeroth-Order Queries, Jingyi Zhu (Alibaba Group)
  Average-Case Integrality Gap for Non-Negative Principal Component Analysis, Afonso S Bandeira (ETH); Dmitriy Kunisky (New York University), Alex Wein (NYU)
  A Qualitative Study of the Dynamic Behavior for Adaptive Gradient Algorithms, Chao Ma (Princeton University), Lei Wu (Princeton University), Weinan E (Princeton University)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/covid/</guid>
      <description>While we all desire that public health conditions will be safe to allow a MSML21 physical meeting, we acknowledge the uncertainties surrounding the current Covid-19 epidemic, and therefore contemplate the possibility of holding a virtual meeting instead, in case we cannot guarantee the safety of all participants.
Please stay tuned for continuous and further updates by following us on Twitter.
Update: After careful analysis of the situation, we have decided to hold this event Virtual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Dates</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/dates/</guid>
      <description>DEADLINE EXTENSION: December 11th, 2020, 11:59pm (AOE)  Submission deadline: December 4th, 2020, 11:59pm (AOE) December 11th, 2020 (AOE). First round reviews: February 1st, 2021. Revision deadline: March 5th, 2021. Final Decisions : End of March, 2021. Conference: August 16-19th, 2021.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Logistics</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/local/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/local/</guid>
      <description>Stay tuned for local arrangements!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSML Board</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/board/</guid>
      <description>Roberto Car (Chemistry, Princeton University)
  Weinan E (Mathematics, Princeton University)
  Anna Gilbert (Mathematics, Yale University)
  Jan Hesthaven (Mathematics, EPFL)
  George Karniadakis (Applied Mathematics, Brown University)
  Stephane Mallat (Mathematics, College de France, Flatiron Institute and Ecole Normale Superieure)
  Nathan Kutz (Applied Mathematics, University of Washington)
  Nicola Marzari (Materials, EPFL)
  Stanley Osher (Mathematics, UCLA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization and Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/session1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/session1/</guid>
      <description>Chair: Rachel Ward (UT Austin) Time: August 16th, 16:20-17:10 CET  Hessian-Aided Random Perturbation (HARP) Using Noisy Zeroth-Order Queries, Jingyi Zhu (Alibaba Group)  slides video
  Average-Case Integrality Gap for Non-Negative Principal Component Analysis, Afonso S Bandeira (ETH); Dmitriy Kunisky (New York University), Alex Wein (NYU)  slides video
 A Qualitative Study of the Dynamic Behavior for Adaptive Gradient Algorithms, Chao Ma (Princeton University), Lei Wu (Princeton University), Weinan E (Princeton University)  slides video</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plenary Speakers</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/keynote/</guid>
      <description>Marc Mezard Professor, Director of Ecole Normale Superieure, Paris, France.
August 16th
Qianxiao Li Assistant Professor, Department of Mathematics, National University of Singapore
August 19th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Previous Years</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/previous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/previous/</guid>
      <description> MSML20, Virtual Conference.  Chairs: Jianfeng Lu (Duke), Rachel Ward (UT Austin).    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Committee</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/pc/</guid>
      <description>General Chairs  Joan Bruna (New York University) Jan Hesthaven (EPFL) Lenka Zdeborova (EPFL)  Program Chairs  Afonso Bandeira (ETH) Jean Barbier (International Centre for Theoretical Physics) Quentin Berthet (Google) Steven L. Brunton (University of Washington) Chiara Cammarota (Sapienza, University of Rome) Michele Ceriotti (EPFL) Xiuyuan Cheng (Duke University) Lenaic Chizat (CNRS) Kyle Cranmer (NYU) Gábor Csányi (University of Cambridge) Bin Dong (Peking University) Boris Hanin (Princeton University) Shirley Ho (Flatiron Institute) Arnulf Jentzen (University of Munster) Gitta Kutyniok (LMU Munich) Qianxiao Li (NUS) Jianfeng Lu (Duke University) Pankaj Mehta (Boston University) Frank Noe (FU Berlin) Benjamin Peherstofer (NYU) Paris Perdikaris (University of Pennsylvania) Lars Ruthotto (Emory University) Themis Sapsis (MIT) Eric Vanden-Eijnden (NYU) Soledad Villar (Johns Hopkins University) Lei Wang (IOP) Rachel Ward (UT Austin)  Local Committee  Emmanuel Abbé Daniel Kressner Anne-Clemence Corminboeuf Victor Panaretos  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>     ET CET GMT+8 Aug 16th Aug 17th Aug 18th Aug 19th     9:00am-9:10am 15:00-15:10 21:00-21:10 Opening Remarks Computational Mathematics Workshop (Jianfeng Lu, Gitta Kutyniok, Steve Brunton, Afonso Bandeira, Ben Peherstofer, Paris Perdikaris) Computational Physics Workshop (Gabor Csanyi, Kyle Cranmer, Shirley Ho, Michelle Ceriotti) MSML&#39;22 Welcome   9:10am-10:00am 15:10-16:00 21:10-22:00 Marc Mezard Qianxiao Li   10:20am-11:10am 16:20-17:10 22:20-23:10 Session 1: Optimization and Algorithms Session 5: Inverse Problems   11:10am-12:00pm 17:10-18:00 23:10-00:00 Session 2: Learning Foundations I Session 6: Reinforcement Learning and Control   12:20pm-1:10pm 18:20-19:10 00:20-01:10 Session 3: Learning Foundations II Session 7: PDEs and ODEs   1:10pm-2:00pm 19:10-20:00 01:10-02:00 Session 4: High-Dimensional Statistics Session 8: Computational Physics    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>