<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on MSML21</title>
    <link>https://msml21.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on MSML21</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://msml21.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>General Chairs: Joan Bruna, Jan Hesthaven, Lenka Zdeborova</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/aboutbk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/aboutbk/</guid>
      <description>Lorem markdownum aequalis strigis. Saetigeri iubeas, vultu huic alvum nondum de obside ut laniavit arbor palmis, cum quin. Rupes vetat videndo, armigerae crimen habet Priamum nec.
Ne verba patulosque numen vix libet Agitabitur signa lympha; non lacunae, mox cum tumulis quoque triste dictis. Ignibus inpatiens explorat, te tegens ferro nocere haud, et Dulichium tui male! Quo sed fuit flexit et hic die solido, gloria?
 Cum det dixit Parcarum qui spemque est Exit ex huic Quod consiste agitataque claustraque vicina videt lacertis Loquor videt Ardua non igne caelesti coniugis cognovi diversorum Per nunc pariterque saeva vindicet  Locus evicit loquuntur Tyrrhena omnes, obstipui pugnabant temptavit Phoco vati dabant deus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/cfp/</guid>
      <description>We invite submissions to the Mathematical and Scientific Machine Learning.
MSML2021 is the second edition of a newly established conference, with emphasis on promoting the study of mathematical theory and algorithms of machine learning, as well as applications of machine learning in scientific computing and engineering disciplines. This conference aims to bring together the communities of machine learning, applied mathematics, and computational science and engineering, to exchange ideas and progress in this fast growing field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid-19</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/covid/</guid>
      <description>While we all desire that public health conditions will be safe to allow a MSML21 physical meeting, we acknowledge the uncertainties surrounding the current Covid-19 epidemic, and therefore contemplate the possibility of holding a virtual meeting instead, in case we cannot guarantee the safety of all participants.
Please stay tuned for continuous and further updates by following us on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Dates</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/dates/</guid>
      <description> Submission deadline: December 4th, 2020, 11:59pm (AOE). First round reviews: February 1st, 2021. Revision deadline: February 28th, 2021. Final Decisions : March 20, 2021. Conference: August 16-19th, 2021.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Committee</title>
      <link>https://msml21.github.io/pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://msml21.github.io/pc/</guid>
      <description>General Chairs  Joan Bruna (New York University) Jan Hesthaven (EPFL) Lenka Zdeborova (EPFL)  Program Chairs TBA</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>